{

"Bullshit": {"Spreadsheet_Selector": "aapl 3 Statement",

"SheetMappings": {

    "inputs": {
      "name": "Income Statement", 
      "includeRows": ["Income Statement", "Revenue", "Cost of Goods Sold", "Gross Profit", "Operating Expenses", 
                    "Operating Expense", "EBITDA", "Depreciation", "Interest Expense",  "Interest Income",
                   "EBT", "Tax Provision", "Net Income",

            "c",
                   "Assumptions", "Revenue Growth Rate", "COGS / Revenue", "Opex / Revenue"]
    }
  }},



    "1": {
      "name": "What's an Income Statement?",
      "textBoxContent1": "The income statement shows a company’s financial performance over a specific period of time. It tells us how much revenue the business earned, what it spent to earn that revenue, and how much profit or loss it generated as a result.",
      "hint":"none",
      "Qtype": "MCQ",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the income statement?",
        "options": ["To show the company’s financial position at a specific point in time", "To track the changes in cash during a period", "To summarize a company’s revenues and expenses over a period, showing profit or loss", "To report how much equity the company’s shareholders own"],
        "correctAnswer": "To summarize a company’s revenues and expenses over a period, showing profit or loss"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "TabLocked": "False",

        "Quizcels_ROW_5":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 1
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "1": 14,
            "2": 15,
            "3": 16
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "1":  1,
            "2":  2,
            "3":  3,
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }}
    },
    "2": {
      "name": "Revenue",
      "textBoxContent1": "Revenue is the total amount of money a company earns from its core operations, before any expenses are subtracted.",
      "hint":"It's stated in the textbox.",
      "Qtype": "MCQ",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "What is Revenue in 2014?",
        "options": ["470", "3562", "365817", "-1458"],
        "correctAnswer": "365817"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "inputs"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_5":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 1
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "1": 14,
            "2": 15,
            "3": 16
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "1":  1,
            "2":  2,
            "3":  3,
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }},
        "highlightRows":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{ "1" :1}
      }
    },
        "3": {
      "name": "Revenue Growth Rate",
      "textBoxContent1": "One way to forecast revenue growth is by using year on year growth from historical data. This is done by calculating the percentage change in revenue from one year to the next. Use the Excel formula",
      "textBoxContent2": "to find YoY forecasted growth in the highlighted cell.",
      "textBoxContentBOLD": "=(Current Year Revenue - Prior Year Revenue) / ABS(Prior Year Revenue)",
      "hint":"Use this formula: =((E1-D1) / D1)",
      "Qtype": "cells",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "Find the forecasted revenue growth rate",
        "options": ["470", "3562", "2356", "-1458"],
        "correctAnswer": "2356"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "inputs"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_14":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 1
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "1": 14,
            "2": 15,
            "3": 16
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "1":  1,
            "2":  2,
            "3":  3,
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }},
        "highlightRow":{
        "tab": "intro",
        "row": 0
      }
    },
     "4": {
      "name": "Forecasting Revenue",
      "textBoxContent1": "Revenue is forecasted by multiplying the previous year's revenue by the revenue growth rate + 1.",
      "hint":"Use the formula: = E1 * (1 + $B$13) in the first cell and drag it to the other three",
      "Qtype": "cells",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "Forecast Revenue",
        "options": ["470", "3562", "2356", "-1458"],
        "correctAnswer": "2356"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "inputs"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 4,
            "2": 5,
            "3": 6,
            "4": 7
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "2": 15,
            "3": 16
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "1":  1,
            "2":  2,
            "3":  3,
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }},
        "highlightRow":{
        "tab": "intro",
        "row": 0
      }
    },
    "5": {
      "name": "COGS",
      "textBoxContent1": "The second line in most income statements is Cost of Goods Sold. Cost of goods sold or COGS, is the direct expenses needed to make the product that is generating revenue.",
      "hint":"none",
      "Qtype": "MCQ",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "What does COGS stand for?",
        "options": ["Capital Optimization & Growth Strategy", "Cost of Goods Sold", "Credit Operations & Governance Structure", "Cashflow-Oriented Growth System"],
        "correctAnswer": "Cost of Goods Sold"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "projections"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_0":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 4,
            "2": 5,
            "3": 6,
            "4": 7
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "2": 15,
            "3": 16
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "2":  2,
            "3":  3,
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }},
        "highlightRows":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{ "1" :2}
      }
    },
    "6": {
      "name": "How do we Forecast COGS?",
      "textBoxContent1": "COGS is typically forecasted as a % of revenue. To find COGS as a % of revenue, Divide COGS by Revenue in the most recent year of historical data.",
      "hint":"=E2/E1",
      "Qtype": "cells",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "Enter COGS / Revenue into the highlighted cell",
        "options": ["Capital Optimization & Growth Strategy", "Cost of Goods Sold", "Credit Operations & Governance Structure", "Cashflow-Oriented Growth System"],
        "correctAnswer": "Cost of Goods Sold"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "projections"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_15":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 1
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "2": 15,
            "3": 16
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "2":  2,
            "3":  3,
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }},
        "highlightRow":{
        "tab": "intro",
        "row": 0
      }
    },
      "7": {
      "name": "Forecasting COGS",
      "textBoxContent1": "Now that we have COGS as a % of revenue we can multiply revenue for this year times our COGS % to get our COGS for this year.",
      "hint":"use this formula and drag it to the 3 cells =F1*$B$14",
      "Qtype": "cells",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "Forecast COGS",
        "options": ["Capital Optimization & Growth Strategy", "Cost of Goods Sold", "Credit Operations & Governance Structure", "Cashflow-Oriented Growth System"],
        "correctAnswer": "Cost of Goods Sold"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "projections"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_2":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 4,
            "2": 5,
            "3": 6,
            "4": 7
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "3": 16
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "3":  3,
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }},
        "highlightRow":{
        "tab": "intro",
        "row": 0
      }
    },
    "8": {
      "name": "Gross Profit",
      "textBoxContent1": "Gross Profit is the difference between a company’s revenue and its Cost of Goods Sold (COGS). It shows how much the company earns from its core products or services before accounting for operating expenses, interest, taxes, or other costs.",
      "hint":"use the formula =F1 - F2 and drag to fill all cells",
      "Qtype": "cells",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "Enter Gross Profit for the highlighted cells",
        "options": ["Black-Scholes", "CAPM", "Gordon Growth Model", "FIFO"],
        "correctAnswer": "Gordon Growth Model"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "intro"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_3":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 4,
            "2": 5,
            "3": 6,
            "4": 7
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "3": 16
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }}
    },
    "9": {
      "name": "Operating Expenses",
      "textBoxContent1": "Operating expenses are the costs a company incurs from its core business operations, excluding the cost of goods sold. They include items like salaries, rent, marketing, and R&D.",
      "hint":"Just click the thing",
      "Qtype": "MCQ",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "What is operating expense in 2016?",
        "options": [ "46022", "32603", "40241", "43328"],
        "correctAnswer": "43328"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "valuations"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_0":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 4,
            "2": 5,
            "3": 6,
            "4": 7
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "3": 16
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }},
        "highlightRows":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{ "1" :4}
      }
    },
      "10": {
      "name": "How to forecast Operating Expenses",
      "textBoxContent1": "Like many other metrics, Operating Expenses can be forecast as a % of revenue. To do this, divide Operating expense in 2017 by Revenue in 2017",
      "hint":"=E4/E1",
      "Qtype": "cells",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "Find Opex as a % of revenue",
        "options": [ "Freight charges for shipping raw materials", "Depreciation of manufacturing equipmen", "Salaries of the sales team", "Cost of raw materials used in production"],
        "correctAnswer": "Salaries of the sales team"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "valuations"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_16":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 1
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "4":  4,
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }},
        "highlightRows":{
        "tab": "intro",
        "row": 0
      }
    },
      "11": {
      "name": "Forecasting Operating Expenses",
      "textBoxContent1": "Now that we have Operating Expenses as a % of revenue, we can multiply revenue times that percent to forecast Operating Expenses.",
      "hint":"=F1*$B$15",
      "Qtype": "cells",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "Forecast Opex",
        "options": [ "Freight charges for shipping raw materials", "Depreciation of manufacturing equipmen", "Salaries of the sales team", "Cost of raw materials used in production"],
        "correctAnswer": "Salaries of the sales team"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "valuations"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 4,
            "2": 5,
            "3": 6,
            "4": 7
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }}
    },
        "12": {
      "name": "EBITDA",
      "textBoxContent1": "EBITDA stands for Earnings Before Interest, Taxes, Depreciation, and Amortization. It measures a company’s operating performance by showing profit from core business activities before accounting for financial and non-cash expenses. EBITDA is often used to compare profitability across companies and industries.",
      "hint":"=F3-F4",
      "Qtype": "cells",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "Enter Ebitda into the highlighted cells",
        "options": [ "Beakers to study new lemonade flavors", "A company vacation", "Paying your friend to test new flavors", "Depreciation of Lab Coats"],
        "correctAnswer": "A company vacation"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "valuations"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_5":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 4,
            "2": 5,
            "3": 6,
            "4": 7
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "5":  5,
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }}
    },

        "13": {
      "name": "Finish",
      "textBoxContent1": "The rest of the metrics on the income statement can't be forecasted without information from the Balance sheet or Cash flow statement. After you have completed the modules on the Balance sheet and Cash flow statement, their will be a final module wrapping up the model covering these and other metrics. Answer the final question to complete the module.",
      "hint":"none",
      "Qtype": "MCQ",
      "quiz": {
        "question": "How did you forecast COGS?",
        "options": [ "as a % of Revenue based on historical data", "By totalling forecasted costs", "By subtracting Operational Expenses from Gross Profit", "By forecasting as a % of Gross Profit"],
        "correctAnswer": "as a % of Revenue based on historical data"
      },
      "targetTab": "none",
      "spreadsheetConfig": {
        "initialTab": "valuations"
      },
        "Quizcels_ROW_0":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "cols":{
            "1": 4,
            "2": 5,
            "3": 6,
            "4": 7
    }}, 
        "Blankcels_COL_1":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
    }}, 
        "BlankFORs_COL_4":{
        "tab": "inputs",
        "rows":{
            "6":  6,
            "7":  7,
            "8":  8,
            "9":  9,
            "10":  10,
            "11":  11
        }},
        "highlightRow":{
        "tab": "intro",
        "row": 0
      }
    }
  }